

Andrii Andreiev, Swift Developer

Short summary: 10+ years of development (swift, flash, VHDL) 2 years of management

KYIV, UKRAINE · commovere@gmail.com · +38 068 373 08 61 · t.me/andrei andreiev

High efficient and self-motivated Swift Developer who enjoys finding elegant solutions to non-trivial problems. Focused on the goal and driven by visual sophistication and laser-sharp precision, I take pride in every finished project, and never stop learning along the way.

Specialties: Solving IT problems and getting things done, quickly and efficiently. I can view the larger picture, analyze the situation, and devise and implement a strategy to achieve the desired outcome.

I am proficient in Swift, algorithms, math

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Tech Lead at NDA Sep 2020 — present, Kyiv

Design and development iOS and macOS apps. Small-to-midsize projects in the privacy protection area. My main responsibilities: team leading, tasks distribution, features development, release management, cross team communication

iOS Tech Lead at Sensogram Technologies (startup) Mar 2019 — Aug 2020, Kyiv

Design and development medical applications (for public use and for medical testing) https://www.sensogram.com. Small size project for 5 devs, 1 UX/UI designer, without QAs, PMs or other. My main responsibilities: team leading, tasks distribution, features development, testing, publishing apps, agile coaching

Software Engineer/Team Lead, PM at **PDFFiller/airSlate** (product) Aug 2015 — Mar 2019, Kyiv

As Project Manager (Apr 2017 - Mar 2019): Managed 4 teams (2 iOS and 2 Android), 7 projects (PDFfiller, SignNow, Scan2Fill, AltoApps, SingleForms, airSlate, desktop utils, some small NDA projects). My main responsibilities: resource planning, agile coaching, features delivery controlling, tasks distribution, team motivating

As Swift developer (Sep 2016 - Mar 2019): design and developing pdffiller iOS client, developing multiple small iOS apps, developing macOS utils. Small and mid size projects for 4 (at beginning) to 29 (in 2019) IT-specialists. My main responsibilities: developing and maintaining iOS apps, developing macOS utils, some scripting (js, ruby, python, bash), publishing apps to Apple App Store

As Senior Flash developer (Aug 2015 - Sep 2016): design and developing web online document editor https://www.pdffiller.com. Big size projects for 10+ (at beginning) to 500+ (in 2019) IT-specialists. My main responsibilities: maintaining pdf document editor, cross team mini projects, new features development

KEYWORDS

swift, Xcode, iOS, macOS, data structure, algorithms, OOP, git, json, xml, REST, jira, team leading, project management, agile, scrum, estimation, requirement management

LINKS

LinkedIn

Some of IT conferences I was a speaker: video#1, video#2, video#3, video#4

LANGUAGES

Ukrainian (native), Russian (native), English (intermediate)

EDUCATION

2001-2005 BD in Computer Systems, Sloviansk College NAU

2005-2010 MD in Computer Science, National Aviation University of Ukraine

Offline courses:

Project Management Bootcamp (Hillel IT School)

SoftSkills in IT (PArts Edu)

Online courses:

Algorithms: Design and Analysis (Stanford University),

Algorithms (Princeton University),

Communication skills for Engineering Leaders (Rice University)

Python essentials for scripting (JBootcamp)

HOBBIES

reading, shamanic drums, cooking

Senior Flash Developer/Team Lead at Win Interactive LLC (outsource)

Jan 2013 — Aug 2015, Kyiv

Design and developing couple casino projects (slots, roulette, blackjack) <u>StardustCasino</u> <u>SlotsCraze</u>. Mid size projects for 5-7 client (flash/frontend) devs, remote backend team, remote QA team, remote PMs. My main responsibilities: team leading, gathering requirements from client, business trips, developing slot games for existing slot-engine, developing blackjack game from scratch, porting web-plugin games to mobile, publishing to Apple App Store

Flash Developer at AlternativaPlatform (product) Jan 2012 — Jan 2013, Perm

Developing flash clients (web-plugin client, iOS+Android GPU accelerated client) for 3D MMORPG http://tankionline.com . Big size project for 100+ IT-specialists. My main responsibilities: UI of chat, UI and networking of auth, StarWars+Lego demo for AdobeMax 2012, Stage3D port of TankiOnline game for iOS+Android (as 1 of 2 developers team), taking part in IT conferences as speaker

Flash Developer at Cogniance (outsource) Mar 2011 — Jan 2012, Kyiv

Developing flash multiplayer card games https://www.playsino.com. Mid size project for 3 Flash devs, 3 PHP dev2, 1 designer, 2 QAs, 1 PM. I developed one of the games from scratch and took part in game engine development. My main responsibilities: implement turn-base logic for card games, update networking layer (it was long polling approach), program animation development

Developing a flash client of music service for Facebook https://gmusic.com. Small project for 1 Flash dev, 1 PHP dev, 1 designer, 1 QA, 1 PM. I developed a project from scratch. My main responsibilities: implement music player with upload feature, implement dynamic UI themes support, facebook integration, requirements management

Flash Developer, Daxx BV (outsource) Sep 2010 — Mar 2011, Kyiv

Developing a full-flash browser-based MMORPG https://innebula.com. Small project for 1 Flash dev, 1 PHP dev, 1 designer, no QAs, PMs or other. I became a team member when the project was almost finished. My main responsibilities: optimize rendering of 3D objects, rework main screen with animations, update networking layer, testing, reporting to owner

REFERENCES

Vadim Yasinovsky, airSlate vadim@airslate.com